Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Prudential Land Co. - Tehama County ”., 1915-1918 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - “Conveyances by Charles Crocker, Contract & Finance Co., P.I. Co. in Butte, Colusa, El Dorado, Glenn, Kings and Los Angeles Counties”. Abstracts made, 1906-1907. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - “Conveyances by Chas. Crocker, Contract & Finance Co., P.I. Co. in San Joaquin, San Luis Obispo, Santa Cruz, Shasta and Siskiyou Counties”. Most abstracts except 2nd Siskiyou abstract, dated 1907, 1921. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - “Conveyances by Chas. Crocker, Contract & Finance, P.I. Co. in Sonoma, Sutter, Stanislaus (Calif.), Cochise (Arizona), Elko (Nevada) and Jackson (Oregon) Counties”. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - “Nevada Land - Leases - Fultons Sale, Pierce 1922”. Land in Washoe County, Nevada. Includes history of how land was acquired by Big Four, held by Crocker and passed on at his death to P.I. Co., 1913-1922 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - “White Oaks, New Mexico Lands, Sale to Fulmer ”. J.H. Fulmer Jr., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - “Buffalo, New York”. Sale of part of land owned jointly by P.I. Co. and the Estates of B.C. & D.P. Rumsey to Samuel Dark and Ward Wickwire Correspondence and reports concerning collection of payment and rest of Buffalo land runs to, 6/28/1916. 1934. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - “Texas Lands”. Bound volume - Alfred Abeel, Master Commissioner, Deed to Wilbur F. Boyle, recorded Other deeds to Boyle same year., 1898. (Box 6, Folder 24)
- P.I. Townsites
  - “General Quitclaim Correspondence (Intra-office, Multitownsite, Town Unidentified)”. Correspondence, dates 9/25/20 - 6/27/66. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - “Land - Outstanding Contracts for the Year Ending ”., 12/31/11 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - “Cashmere Colony Tract, Yolo County (Capay Valley Land Co.)”. Two leases: Correspondence, 1. Nov. 1909, 2. Jan. 1917. 9/24/63 to 4/25/66. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - “Coalinga, Fresno County”. Letter of Administration (Superior Ct.) Certificate of Title correspondence, 10/14/1909, 10/8/20, 5/26/36 to 5/13/49. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - “Colfax”. Correspondence re: quitclaim deed for certain Colfax property., May - June 1945 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - “Colton, San Bernadino County”. Contract for a deed, 8/1/16. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - “Corning, Tehama County”. Correspondence and quitclaim deed, 6/24/36 - 5/26/47. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - “Cottonwood, Shasta County”. Correspondence, Right of Way and Track Map of Southern Pacific and Quitclaim Deed., Nov. 23, 1965 - Jan. 26, 1966. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - “Cromir, Fresno County”. Copy of original deed to South. Pacific 5/29, map, correspondence and quitclaim deed, 1894, May to August 1945. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - “Crow's Landing, Stanislaus County”. Correspondence and quitclaim deeds, 10/26/32 - 10/17/44. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - “Delano, Kern County”. Quitclaim deed request and P.I. Co. response, Sept. - Oct. 1937. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - “Dinuba, Tulare County”. Townsite Agreement, contract, leases, correspondence 4/8, Includes notification of lawsuit brought by town of Dinuba against P.I. Co. and others, 1888 to 8/24/47. (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - “Dos Palos, Merced County”. Correspondence with District Attorney's Office of Merced re: Quitclaim Deed, April - May 1953. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - “Dunsmuir, Siskiyou County”. Three maps and correspondence, 9/30/35 - 11/19/41. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - “East Bakersfield, Kern Count (Formerly Summer)”. Document from Kern County Abstract Co. re: mapping of certain lot, 7/31/06. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - “East Oakland, Alameda County”. Notes on collection of rent, July 1906 - 1/13/10. (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - “Earlimart, Tulare County (Formerly Alila)”. Correspondence with Tulare County Abstract Co. re: quitclaim deed, September 1939. (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - “Elko, Nevada”. Correspondence and legal suits, 1/26/37 - July 1955. (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - “El Verano, Sonoma County (El Vernano Villa Assn., El Verano Improvement Assn.)”. Correspondence, leases, contracts for deeds, 11/14/88 - 3/21/66. (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - “Esparto, Yolo County (Capay Valley Land Co.)”. Lease issued to A.H. Fredson, 11/1/11. (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - “Exeter, Tulare County”. Letter of Administration, Superior Court, Certificate of Title and correspondence, 2/15/10 - 2/27/39. (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - “Famoso, Kern County”. Three contracts for deeds Another agreement declaring the one of null and void. Finally, correspondence re: quitclaim deed., 3/28/96, 3/9/10, 3/16/10. (12/18/17) March 1896 5/18/30 - 6/4/38 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - “Firebaugh, Fresno County”. Townsite Agreement, Report of Title and correspondence, 5/5/91 - 9/14/59. (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - “Fowler, Fresno County”. Certificate of Title, contracts for deeds, correspondence and map, 4/21/11 - 3/8/51. (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - “Fruto, Colusa County”. Townsite Agreement, leases, quitclaim deed, correspondence, July 10, 1888 - Oct. 3, 1960. (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - “Galt, Sacramento County”. History of Galt, Declaration of Trust (and cancellation thereof), quitclaim deeds, contracts for deeds, map, correspondence, May 1916 - Nov. 1953. (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - “Gosford, Kern County”. Two townsite agreements between P.I. Co. and Kern County Land Co.: 1. 2., Sept. 13, 1892, Dec. 18, 1917. (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - “Gridley, Butte County”. Correspondence. quitclaim deed and map, 2/16/33 - 1/12/50. (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - “Guinda Colony Tract, Yolo County (Capay Valley Land Co.)”. Leases, contracts for deeds Correspondence re: quitclaim deeds, Nov. 15, 1912 - June 1, 1919. March and April 1953. (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - “Hanford, Kings County”. Two quitclaims deeds and relating correspondence: 1. 2., June - August, 1939, June 1951. (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - “Hardwick, Kings County”. Correspondence re: quitclaim deed including copy of original deed and map, Jan. - Feb. 1963. (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - “Herndon, Fresno County”. Receipts Correspondence re: quitclaim deed, 1/3/13. Sept. - Oct. 1944. (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - “Hickman, Stanislaus County”. Townsite agreement certificate to title copy of `Instructions and Rules to Real Estate Brokers Governing the Sale of P.I. Co. Properties'. Correspondence re: quitclaim deed, July 1890, 4/22/19, Nov. 1955. (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - “Hornbrook, Siskiyou County”. Correspondence and quitclaim deeds, 12/30/49 - 11/2/65. (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - “Huron, Fresno County”. Three leases Then correspondence and map, Dec. 1914 - August 1915. 3/15/37 - 4/22/58. (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - “Ingomar, Merced County”. Correspondence, quitclaim deed, map, 5/24/61 - 11/13/61. (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - “Ivesta, Fresno County (Formerly Minneola)”. Lease two copies of contract for deed, (10/1/12), (1/3/17). (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - “Jasmin, Kern County”. Superior Ct. letter of administration - estate of Jean Sarrazin, (4/15/10). (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - “Lathrop, San Joaquin County”. Correspondence, 8/5/33 - 1/16/47. (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - “Lemoore, Kings County”. Contracts and correspondence, 8/7/08 - 9/15/58. (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - “Lethene, Kings County”. Correspondence and contract for deed, Dec. 1922 - 4/25/25. (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - “Locans, Fresno County”. Correspondence, map and quitclaim deed, P.I. Co. land to Southern Pacific, dates 7/16/63 - 5/24/65. (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - “Los Angeles”. Correspondence, lists of P.I. Co. land, 1907 - 1909. (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - “Los Banos, Merced County”. Quitclaim deed Then correspondence and other quitclaim deeds, (6/7/18). 2/18/49 - 5/2/51. (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - “Lovelock, Nevada”. Correspondence, 5/15/34 - 3/31/39. (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - “McMillan Tract, Yolo County (Capay Valley Land Co.)”. Six leases, 10/1/08 - 10/1/15. (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - “McMullin, Fresno County”. Correspondence re: quitclaim deed request, June, 1965. (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - “Maxwell, Colusa County”. Agreement, lease, Superior Court. letter of administration, correspondence, map, dates range August 15, 1878 - May 18, 1910. (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - “Mayhew Tract, Talare County”. Copy of agreement, 10/10, 1893. (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - “Mendota, Fresno County”. Copy of townsite agreement then correspondence and quitclaim deeds, (2/5/91). 7/6/42 - 12/17/57. (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - “Merced, Marced County”. Omnious Deed (L. Stanford, et. al. to P.I. Co.), legal suit, mortgage, financial reports, correspondence, dates Feb. 26, 1889 - April 14, 1901. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - “Modesto, Stanislaus County”. Legal suit (Copy of Summons and Complaint), correspondence, 6/13/23 - 10/25/44. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - “Mojave, Kern County”. Agreements, mortgage, certificates of title, contracts for deeds, notes, lists of property, correspondence, quitclaim deeds, map, 7/1/06 - 12/31/63. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - “Montague, SiskiyouCounty”. Leases, contracts for deeds, legal suits (P.I. Co. Plaintiff), correspondence, quitclaim deed, legal suit (P.I. Co. defendant), dates 1/7/08 - 5/26/61. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - “Montpellier, Stanislaus County”. Townsite agreement lease then correspondence re: quitclaim deeds, (6/3/1889), (10/10/16), 11/14/58 - 5/5/60. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - “Mount Shasta, Siskiyou County (Formerly Sisson)”. Correspondence, map quitclaim deed, grant deed, 4/8/36 - 10/17/63. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - “Nelson, Butte County”. Copy of lease, 5/9/17. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - “Newhall, Los Angeles County”. Contract for deed (copy) correspondence, 1/17/18, 3/20/34 - 3/13/46. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - “Newman, Stanislaus County”. Townsite agreement memorandum of Agreement agreement then correspondence and quitclaim deeds, (5/3/87), (2/3/88), (2/5/10), 5/29/35 - 3/20/58. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - “Nord”. Letter, 9/13/48. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - “Orland, Colusa County”. Handwritten townsite agreement correspondence and quitclaim deeds, April 7, 1882 - Aug. 20, 1888, Jan. 18 1937 - Dec. 14, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - “Orris, Tulare County”. Townsite Agreement (2) leases, (Aug. 9, 1888), Dec. 23, 1913 and Sept. 1, 1915. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - “Oswald, Sutter County”. Notes on deeds Small map/, (5/23/1889-8/1/1896). (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - “Palermo, Butte County”. Cop of townsite agreement correspondence re: quitclaim deed, 10/17/1889, Jan. and Feb. 1945. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - “Parker Tract, Folo Count (Capay Valley Land Co.)”. Leases and contracts for deeds., Dates: 1/15/1914 & 1/25/17. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - “Pollasky, Fresno County”. Original memo of agreement correspondence, (11/13/07), 12/18/35 - 3/18/36. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - “Porterville, Tulare County”. Deed townsite agreement and typed copy agreement then correspondence and quitclaim deed, (4/14/1888), (4/13/1888), (4/13/07), 6/19/23 - 3/3/64. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - “Redlands, Riverside County”. Correspondence and quitclaim deed P.I.C. to Southern Pacific, (July 1967). (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - “Reedley, Fresno County”. Townsite agreement, contract, lease, correspondence and quitclaim deed, 5/4/1888 - 4/20/45. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - “Reedley - Abstract of Title”. Bound volume in folder. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - “Reno, Washoe County, Nevada”. Correspondence and quitclaim deed, (4/6/37 - 9/27/44). (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - “Rio Bravo, Kern County”. Agreement and re: lease to P.I. Co., 12/13/23. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - “Rocklin, Placer County”. Correspondence and quitclaim deed, 7/6/36 - 3/27/45. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - “Rolinda, resno County”. Correspondence, quitclaim deed, map, 2/28 - 12/6, 1935. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - “Rumsey, Yolo County”. Capay Valley Land Co. - leases, contracts for needs Then P.I. Co. correspondence re: quitclaim, 10/1/1908 - 1/2/1914. July 20 - Aug. 4, 1954. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - “Ryer, Merced County”. Townsite agreement, leases, release, cancelled check then - abstract of title (includes map) in booklet., 2/24/1893 - 2/23/1921 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - “San Miguel, San Luis Obispo County”. Lease correspondence, (9/7/1914, 12/27/40 - 3/15/44. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - “Sanger, Fresno County”. correspondence for quitclaim deeds correspondence and quitclaim deeds, (2/7/11 - 12/4/1914), (4/20/1941 - 12/15/64). (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - “San Joaquin County”. Map and legal suit (P.I. Co. as one of defendants). (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - “Santa Margarita, San Luis Obispo County. Contracts for deeds, correspondence and quitclaim deed abstract of title (with map) in booklet., (11/29/13 - 10/18/50) (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - “Santa Monica, Los Angeles Count”. Correspondence and legal suit (P.I. Co. as defendant), 11/8/1906 - 7/25/1935. (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - “Saticoy, Ventura County”. Contract, right of way, quitclaim deed and correspondence, 12/13/12 - 9/11/52. (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - “Sespe, Ventura County”. Deed, contracts, law suits (P.I. Co. as plaintiff), leases, notes and figures (undated), map, correspondence, (7/11/1887 - 1/31/1908). (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - “Stanley, Fresno County”. Copy of townsite agreement redemption of real estate, release, correspondence, (9/18/1891), June 1921 - Nov. 1923. (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - “Stevens, Kern County”. Copy of townsite agreement 2nd agreement, (9/13/1892), (12/18/1917). (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - “Sweitzer Tract, Yolo County (Capay Valley Land Co.)”. Copy of lease, 9/30/1915. (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - “Tarusa, Tulare County”. Release of heirs original and copy of contract for deed, (2/11/15), (6/5/20). (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - “Tehachapi, Kern County”. Receipt correspondence and legal suits (P.I. Co. - defendant). Date:, (8/24/1907), (3/25/37 - 8/3/66). (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - “Terra Bella, Tulare County”. Copy of townsite a agreement accompanying latter, (5/7/1888) - (10/8/07). (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - “Tipton, Tulare County”. Tipton-Crocker deeds (abstracts) lease correspondence re: quitclaim deeds, 1884 - 1902, (1/9/15), (6/18/38 - 3/13/41). (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - “Tracy, San Joaquin County”. Correspondence re: quitclaim deeds, (7/19/33 - 12/14/61). (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - “Traver, Tulare County”. Correspondence, lease, agreement, corporate resolutions, law suit (P.I. Co. as defendant), quitclaim deed., Dates: 8/31,1895 - 4/20, 1950. (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - “Truckee, Nevada County”. Correspondence, quitclaim deeds, legal suits (P.I. Co. as sole defendant)., Dates: Nov. 25, 1935 - Sept. 16, 1966. (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - “Tudor, Sutter County”. Note on deeds two leases, (1893), 1/1/07 and 10/7/10. (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - “Tulare, Tulare County”. Correspondence re: quiet title August, legal suit - summons and complaint, P.I. Co., as defendant., 1947 and March 1950 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - “Verdi, Washoe County, Nevada”. Correspondence including maps, sales options, 4/7/61 - 6/10/68. (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - “Vina, Tehama County”. Correspondence and quitclaim deed Last letter in file re: same matter to P.I. Co. from A.E. Roth, Comptroller, Stanford University, Feb. 1935. (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - “Volta, Merced County”. Townsite a agreement, (11/9/1905). (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - “Wadsworth, Washoe County, Nevada”. correspondence and quitclaim deed, (August, 1962). (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - “Waterford, Stanislaus”. Townsite agreement contracts for deeds, correspondence, certificate of title, quitclaim deeds, (1/26/1891), (2/20/13 - 3/2/48). (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - “Weins Tract, Yolo County (Capay Valley Land Co.)”. Two leases, (11/15/11). (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - “Wells, Elko County, Nevada”. Abstract of title (not bound), contracts for deed, correspondence, deed of confirmation, legal suits (P.I. Co. as one of defendants)., Dates: August 7, 1920 - May 13, 1953. (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - “Westley, Stanislaus County”. Examination and cancellation of townsite agreement., (4/18/1888) (2/26/18) (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - “Wible Orchard, Kern County”. Cop of townsite agreement new agreement, (9/13/1892), (12/18/17). (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - “Willows, Glenn County”. Correspondence re: quitclaim deed, 3/10 - 6/3, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - “Winnemucca, Humboldt County, Nevada”. Correspondence, quitclaim deeds, map, legal suit (P.I. Co. as defendant)., Dates: 4/22/35 - 4/13/65. (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - “Yarmouth, San Joaquin County”. Deed, (Oct. 16, 1914). (Box 8, Folder 57)
- Carbon Hill Coal Co.
  - “Carbon Hill Coal- Stock certificate”. List of stock owned by P.I. Co., 1892 and 1923 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Qualification to do business - Washington”. Secretary of (Washington) State document, annual license for P.I. Co. to operate in washington corporation licenses for C.H.C.C., correspondence, (1908 - 1915), Dates: 6/15/08 - 7/1/1966. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, Dissolution - 1966”. Correspondence between directors and lawyers, legal documents of Dissolution (Washington and California State). Everything date (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - “Auditor's Reports, Carbon Hill”. for years, 1923 & 1927. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal - Corporation, Income tax”. Tax returns, some correspondence and financial reports, 1936 - 1966. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal - Sale to Pacific Coast Co., 1924 - Sale, Supplemental, Liquidation Contracts”. 1st item - list of contents of folder and, dates 8/28/24 - 10/1/47. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, Correspondence 1906 - 1949”. letter from George Crocker, predominantly correspondence between P.I. Co. and Pacific Coast Coal Co. officials, inventory of C.H.C.C. propert Copy of Enumclaw Courier-Herald, with history of Carbonado. much correspondence between S.F.B. Morse - George Hopkins., 12/5, 1906 - 10/1/47 7/29/48 - 1948-49 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, General Correspondence ”. Includes inter-organizational memos, quitclaim and grant deed issued by C.H.C.C., 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, General Correspondence 1960”. (end), great deal of correspondence with Sheridan Hopkins who became P.I. Co. representative after death of his father, George, copy of Buckley New-Banner carrying story re: sale of Wilkeson Mine to Japanese concern, more newspaper articles - same subject, quitclaim deeds., Dec. 1966 2/2/61 - (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, Gopher Mining, 1960-on/Prior Years in 'Correspondence' ”. (ie. Tony Biselli and partners have small mining operation on C.H.C.C. land - correspondence with S.F.B.M. and P.I. Co. through S. Hopkins., 9-7 & 9-8) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - “Carbonado Controversy”. Also covered and explained in listing of JL 16 Box #3. Correspondence between S.F.B. Morse and R.B. Wallace, among others, re: stipuletions of deeds given to people living on C.H.C.C. land. All P.I. Co. Directors, Washington D.C. administrators, U.S. Senators and Congressmen from Washington and Calif. States drawn in to melee. File includes correspondence and some news articles (editorials). Dates:, 11/8/1963 - 8/8/1966. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Consultants Evaluations - Bailey Willis and George Watkin Evans”. Map of Pierce County, Washington, two reports by Bailey Willis (Stanford professor): 1. Memorandum Report on Current Conditions at Carbon Hill Washington 2. Memorandum on the Pocahontas Property, King County, Washington Report by Stephen Knowles, Engineer - Fuel Situation in Seattle and in Western Washington. Market for Smokeless Fuel Estimates of available Tonnage Carbonado Mine Report by R.J. Wulzen Special Report to Directors P.I. Co. re: C.H.C.C. Report by George Watkins Evans, (October 1920), (October 1920). (3/14/1922), (8/23/27). (9/18/36), (Oct. 1936). (4/15/42). (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - “C.H. Coal - Report on Carbon River Hydroelectric Potential Bound volume, report authored by Ashton and Bridgman, Engineers. Date:, 1914”. June 1914 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, Index to Voucher Record ”. Old notebook., 1918-1924 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal - Bank Statements, Cancelled Checks ”., 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal - Sample Checks and Vouchers ”. Cross reference to JL001., 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Map or Carbonado drawn for Insurance Purposes”., 5/1/16 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Pierce County Official Maps”. Eight maps by section, undated. (Box 9, Folder 18)
- C.H.C.C., Pacific Coast Commercial Co., Ione Coal & Iron Co., Rocky Mountain Coal & Iron Co.
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Reports ”. Different financial reports (typed copies)., June - Oct. 1910 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Reports - ”. Same as 10-1., Jan. - June, Nov. - Dec. 1911 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Inventories ”. Five inventories: 1. general 2. machinery and tools 3. store rooms 4. hotel 5. store and butcher shop., 12/31/10 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. In entories ”. Six inventories 1-5 same as 10-3. 6. Betterment Account., 12/31/11 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. Inventories ”. One all-inclusive inventory., 12/31/23 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, Mine Inventory - Sale to Pacific Coast, ”. Includes map of mines., 9/15/24 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal, Store Inventory - Sale to Pacific Coast ”., 9/15/24 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - “Pacific Coast Commercial Co.”. Articles of incorporation, by-laws, Washington State documents, tax forms, bill of sale to C.H.C.C. correspondence, certificates of dissolution and other documents, re: dissolution. Pacific Coast Commercial Co. was a general merchandizing store in Carbonado., (9/27/15), Dates: 7/31/13 - 5/4/34. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - “Pacific Coast Commercial Co.”. Financial reports (ie. accounts payable, collection sheets) related correspondence., Dates: 1/24/1914 - 9/30/1915. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - “Ione Coal & Iron Correspondence, Deeds, Etc. 1901 - 1929”. Handwritten receipts deed, predominantly correspondence, quiet title action suit by People of California. v. Ione Coal and others. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - “Ione Coal & Iron Co.”. Sample stock certificate, financial sheets, reports on mine and map of mine., Dates: Jan. 1902 - July 1907. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - “Ione Coal & Iron Co., Crocker Bank Deposit Books, ”. Two bank books and financial statements., 1906-1921 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - “Ione Coal & Iron Co., Cancelled Checks”., Dates: July 30, 1904 - Feb. 27, 1907. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - “Hocky Mountain Coal & Iron Co. - Corporate Papers”. Articles of Incorporation - Wyoming State document, certificate of filing in Calif., copies of documents - proxies, certificates, court decisions, licenses., Dates: 9/24/06 - 8/5/20. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - “Rocky Mountain Coal Co.”. Agreements, contracts, leases, map of mines, list of stockholders largest single stockholder trustees of Leland Stanford Junior University), correspondence., (Nov. 1918 - Dates: 4/1/07 - 3/19/21. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - “Rocky Mountain Merchantile Co.”. Sale of R.H. Merchantile and Coal & Iron Co. to George Dexton., Dates: Dec. 1919 - Oct. 9, 1923. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- O.W.F. Co. (Oakland Waterfront Co.)
  - “O.W.F. - Index to Company's Records”. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - “The Oakland Water Front Company - Corporate Papers”. Certificate of Incorporation copy), certificate of Extension of Corporate Existence original and copy), stock ownership certificates, application for dissolution excerpts from Minutes of Director's Meetings, (3/27/1868, (3/15/1918, (1922), (1910 - 1913). (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Meeting Notices & Proxies”., Dates: June 22, 1906 - May 27, 1922. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - “O.W.F. - Stockholders, Settlements of Estates - Chas. H. Tweed, Juliet Waite Garber, Belle Garber Palache”., Dates: 1908 - 1917. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Abstracts of Title”. Include maps, dates 1912 - 1917. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - “Abstract” of title as to property in Alameda Marsh., Dates: 11/6/16. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - “O.W.F. - Quitclaim correspondence” and copies of “Summons and Complaint” in legal suits, 3/6/1933 - 5/3/1946 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Indenture of Trust, - P.I. Co. and O.W.F. Co.”, 4/12/17 (Box 11, Folder 8)